# **Husseyn Smili**

Dubai, UAE

+971561794222 | hsmili@gmail.com | Nationality: American

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A versatile professional with an entrepreneurial mindset in and out of the corporate world. I have 10 years of relationship management and business development experience at top fier global banks focusing on acquiring and managing clients and assets across the MENA region.

#### **EDUCATION**

IE Business School Madrid, Spain

MBA Master of Business Administration

January 2016 - December 2016

- Creator of <u>www.mimble.co</u>
- Co-founder of IE Fin-Tech Club
- Coordinator of IE Basketball Team

# **University of Toledo**

Ohio, United States of America

B.B.A Bachelor of Business Administration

August 2003 - December 2005

• Received Dean's List Honors for academic excellence, Spring 2004 and Spring 2005

Member of Alpha Kappa Psi – The Professional Business Fraternity

**American University of Beirut** 

Beirut, Lebanon

B.B.A Bachelor of Business Administration September 2001 - July 2003

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### ABN AMRO Bank N.V.

### Director, Relationship Manager

**Dubai, United Arab Emirates** 

November 2011 - January 2016

- Focusing on new business development, increased growth of Middle East business by bringing in new assets from high/ultra high net-worth individuals, institutions and family offices in the MENA region
- Exceeded revenue targets each year by building on relationships with new and existing clients
- Conducted research and analysis across all major asset classes to advise and consult clients on bespoke investment strategies in both developed and emerging markets

# Merrill Lynch Bank (Suisse) S.A. (Private Banking)

**Dubai, United Arab Emirates** 

Assistant Vice President

 March 2007 - November 2011

 Managed assets for high/ultra high net-worth individuals, family offices and institutions across the MENA

Received First Vice President award for exceeding annual revenue targets

 Consulted and collaborated across different teams and departments to optimize client investment portfolios and succession planning structures

# **Ed-Smiles Import/Export Company**

Shanghai, China

Partner

July 2006 - February 2007

 Built relationships with manufacturers and vendors of cement, wood and textiles in China, to market and sell to distributors in Bahrain, Saudi Arabia, Lebanon and Jordan

#### **Smiles Telecommunications**

New Mexico, USA

Partner

December 2005 - July 2006

Led and executed roll out of a new prepaid cellular phone company in New Mexico, partnering with over 30 retail outlets and the third largest wholesaler in New Mexico

## LANGUAGES

English (Native), Arabic (Native), Spanish (Conversational)

#### OTHER INTERESTING INFORMATION

- Created an online saving platform, <u>www.mimble.co</u>; IE venture lab selected finalist
- Co-Founded The Clean Team, a cleaning services company with 25 full time employees
- Co-Founded Mr. Shattaf, a travel accessory brand supplied to retail outlets in the UAE and Saudi Arabia
- Active volunteer in charities for refugees in Lebanon